JESSICA M. LOGGANS

978 BEN FRANKLIN HWY E • DOUGLASSVILLE, PA 19518 • PHONE: 267-559-1361 • E-MAIL: JESSICALOGGANS@GMAIL.COM

OBJECTIVE

To help students of all ages become responsible and productive citizens, effective decision-makers, and life-long learners through active learning and participation, being committed to providing a nurturing environment maximizing the potential of every child.

PROFILE

Motivated, personable business professional with a college degree and a successful track record of profitable job experience. Talent for quickly mastering content material. Diplomatic and tactful with professionals and non-professionals at all levels. Accustomed to handling sensitive, confidential records, as is important in dealing with children and their privacy rights.

Flexible and versatile — able to maintain a sense of humor under pressure. Poised and competent with demonstrated ability to easily transcend cultural differences. Excellent team-building skills.

SKILLS

- Active participation in High Point Baptist Chapel (Nursery)
- Managing classroom for diverse populations
- Teaching, tutoring, and counseling
- Technological instruction
- Interactive teaching/learning
- Tailoring curriculum plans

- Positive learning environment
- Learning style assessment
- Computer proficient
- Group learning mechanics
- CPR/First Responder certified
- Professional Presentations

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CERTIFICATIONS

- First Responder certified.
- South Carolina Certification in Early Childhood Education, Pre K-3, achieved May 2012
- Pennsylvania Certification in Early Childhood Education, Pre K-3, achieved April 2013

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Customer relations
 - Greeted and assisted customers.
 - Answered phones and responded to customer inquiries.
 - Input data into multiple computer programs
 - Responsible for schedule making
- Teaching
 - Create Long-Range plans and short-range plans for the school year
 - Create and administer a classroom behavior and incentive plan
 - Teacher-parent relations (encouraging parent involvement)
 - Attended multiple Professional Development conferences
 - Assisted administration in curriculum guide and curriculum development
 - Technology integration
 - Interdisciplinary teaching approaches
 - Mainstream education

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

ELEMENTARY TEACHER - HIGH POINT BAPTIST ACADEMY {GEIGERTOWN, PA}

SEPTEMBER 2012 - PRESENT

- 2013-2015: 5th grade teacher (all subjects)
- 2012-2013: 6th grade teacher (Science, Math, & English). Reading Groups with 1st graders. Administer study hall to 6th, 7th, 9th, and 10th grades. Tutor students

STUDENT TEACHER - OAKWOOD ELEMENTARY SCHOOL (SIMPSONVILLE, SC)

JANUARY 2012 - MAY 2012

2nd grade teacher under the supervision of Amber Gilbert

PATIENT SERVICE REPRASENTATIVE - CANCER CENTER TREATMENT OF AMERICA (PHILADELPHIA, PA)

JUNE 2010 - DECEMBER 2011

- ❖ Customer service to patients & followed dietary restrictions for each patient
- Responsible for at least 10-14 patients each meal. Interacted and served patients, caregivers, and multiple employees

FILE CLERK - SCHWARTZ & BLAKMAN, ATTORNEYS AT LAW {PHILADELPHIA, PA}

OCTOBER 2006 - AUGUST 2008

- Client correspondence, data input, organize and keep track of important client information
- Responsible for safe keeping of client's personal information
- Assistant to Philip Blackman, ESQ. and Stacy Schwartz, ESQ

EDUCATION

BON JONES UNIVERSITY, B.S. {GRADUATION - MAY 2012 | AREAS OF STUDY - EARLY CHILDHOOD EDUCATION}

- The Early Childhood Education (Pre-K-3rd Grade) major provides preparation and practical experience for teaching in pre-kindergarten through the third grade of elementary school. It focuses on producing concerned and clear-thinking teachers. It also develops the ability to generate fresh, original lessons without undue dependence on structured teacher's manuals. This program requires 53 hours in the comprehensive major.
 - GPA: 3.15/4.0
 - Licensed to teach in South Carolina and Pennsylvania.
- Franklin Towne Charter High School
 - Graduation, June 2008
 - GPA: 3.74/4.0